<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on NetKet</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Home on NetKet</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright 2019-2022, The Netket authors - All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 17:48:04 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>/get_involved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 18:02:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>/get_involved/</guid><description>Getting In Touch with the community Users and developers of NetKet hang out in the following places:
GitHub Discussions: we encourage users who have questions about NetKet and Neural Quantum States in general to start a discussion thread. We like them because they are not ephemeral, they are indexed by search engines, and if you get an answer it might benefit other people in the future. GitHub Issues: if you believe you have found a bug, or have a feature request or just want to discuss something to implement in NetKet, we encourage you to start an Issue on GitHub!</description></item><item><title>Citing</title><link>/cite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 18:02:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>/cite/</guid><description>If you find the NetKet project useful for your research, please consider citing our relevant software papers in order to help us to continue devoting time and resources to NetKet development.
The current version of NetKet 3.x is described in our recent preprint arXiv:2112.10526.
NetKet 2.x is described in SoftwareX 10, 100311 (2019). Despite many new features, NetKet 3 still builds on the foundations of the NetKet 2 era too. Therefore, we would appreciate it if you cite both papers in order to continue giving credit to all the authors of NetKet 2 as well.</description></item><item><title>UnitaryHack: Win bounties with NetKet</title><link>/posts/3-unitaryhack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 10:23:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-unitaryhack/</guid><description>NetKet is participating in the 2022 edition of UnitaryHack, kindly sponsored by the quantum non-profit Unitary Fund.
The hackathon will run for two weeks, from Friday, June 3 to Friday, June 17. During the hackathon, several high-profile quantum software projects are each proposing several tasks for which Unitary Fund will provide a bounty to the participant completing the task.
NetKet is participating with 4 bounties to this hackathon, which are worth US$ 300 in total.</description></item><item><title>NetKet-friendly Summer School in Toulouse</title><link>/posts/02-toulouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 10:23:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/02-toulouse/</guid><description>We are glad to advertise that our dear colleagues in Toulouse are organising a Summer school in April on Machine Learning techniques for Quantum Many-Body Physics. The school will feature several lectures and tutorials on NetKet.
Below you can find the original announcement.
Announcement Toulouse School on Machine Learning for Quantum Many-Body Physics
that will take place in Toulouse, France (4th-8th April 2022).
The school will take place in hybrid format (with both online and onsite students and lecturers).</description></item><item><title>Get Started</title><link>/get_started/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 18:02:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>/get_started/</guid><description>QuickStart on the Cloud The simplest way to get started with NetKet is to use Google&amp;rsquo;s Colab, an online notebook environment with access to GPUs. If you have a google, account, simply head to NetKet&amp;rsquo;s documentation, select the first tutorial, and click on the small rocket icon on the top navigation bar. This will launch the tutorial on an online environment that is ready to use.
For example, you can simply click on this button and get started!</description></item><item><title>NetKet 3 ❤️ Jax</title><link>/posts/01-welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/01-welcome/</guid><description>18 months in development, NetKet 3.0 indicates a major new step for the NetKet project. NetKet has been totally rewritten in Python and is now a Jax-based library. This guarantees outstanding performance while allowing researchers to exploit machine-learning frameworks to define advanced Neural-Networks.
GPUs and Google’s TPUs are now supported too!
Update now and try the new examples!</description></item></channel></rss>